<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-wwi-poetry/selected-articles</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045389/1915-02-14/ed-1/seq-45/#words=war+poetry
</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>WHERE poetry Ins helped or hindered either sido In this war I feel quite certain that it is the poetry of the past more than of the present. Poems, in order to he of any real as¬ sistance to hnlicts, must share in tho nrtistie perfection of bullets. Mullets are not created* 011 the spur r>[ the moment; neither are the sort* of poems which infuse a whole nation with uncoiujiiprablo valor. Roth are the result of experience, ripened knowledge,. preparation, de¬ li hurate craftsmanship.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86072143/1916-03-30/ed-1/seq-12/#words=Cap+Greiifell+Jiillnn
</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://tile.loc.gov/storage-services/service/ndnp/pst/batch_pst_davey_ver01/data/sn83045211/00237287654/1918013101/0197.pdf
</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>If Military Work Ended With Training Civil zation Would Receive Tremendous Benefit Instead of Injury Hy GRANTLAND RICE Flanders Field In Flanders Fields the poppies froiu llctwcen the crosses, roiu on row, That marl: our place,' while in ll)c shy TI(C larks, still singing bravely, fly Unheard amid the puns below. We arc the Dead. Short days aqo Wc lived, felt dawn, saw sunsets glow, Loved ana were loved, and now wc lie In Flanders Fields. Take tin onr auarrel with the foe: To jiou from failing hands, wc throw to hold it Mnh; with us who die though poppies blow Colonel John McCrae (in Punch)!i Answer in quiet content that you have drawn. is spent of dawn; has turned on the foe; that you have earned the poppies blow. in endless rest, the Final Inn, each silent crest battle's din; dim wraith by wraith. for your Dead, the faith who've gone ahead. and sway rqw on row"; another day to sunset's nlow. gathers deep guard their shields, Ihc s,.i. i nc torch ; on yours If ye break faith n c snail not sleep, In Flanders Fields. Lieutenant The Living; Slcci), Dreamers, sleep, Through all the peace Until war's final flame Above the silent fields Sleep till the final gun Its crashinq answer Sleep through the dreams In I landers, where Skcp, Dreamers, sleep, 1 on who have reached II here poppies crown Between you and the Steep, Dreamers, sleep, And hold tint message 'The living will not break They owe to those Sojt nc IPlncs tend Between the crosses, And when light sends From flaming dawn, Or when the darkness Where yet the living Let peace eternal crown. That holds your dreams "WV, this fellow icportcd here." the hattetv commander. "I vvondeicd bow bo had ever been passed. He was and Ho was drawn Into a half knot through llicumatism. You could sec that ho had never taken any rcgula cxciclsc or had ever eaten proper food I never had nn Idea he would last twi weeks. And for the first two weeks h camo pietty near fading out. And ther ho began to straighten up n trifle. He began to get his chest out. his shoulders back and his head up. And when' thin began to happen he could see for himself that he was turning back Into a man. That was two months ngo. Today bo b--a good soldier. In good condition, clear-e.veclear skin, erect and on the Joh War kills quite a numbr of men. It Isn't a very good thing taken as a regular dose. But don't forget that it takes many a weakling and half man anil makes him over. If nil war ended with the training a man receives It would be one of the great things of civilization," As to Feet The foundation of a houe or a build in Flanders Fields.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://tile.loc.gov/storage-services/service/ndnp/wa/batch_wa_fir_ver01/data/sn88085187/00211108472/1918032301/0164.pdf
</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Letters Overseas What do you write to your boy over there,” I_etters o'erflowing with grief and despair, Pages filled u|i with your heartaches ami fear? That's not the word for your soldiers to bear. i Smile in n>u> Mwm anno your tears flow; Write all the funniest happenings you know; Describe your spring bonnet, the town's latest fad, And be sure to remember the last joke on Dad. And don't be afraid that your dear soldier lad Will misunderstand If your letter sounds glad. Sure ho'll know that 'tie only the jolliest "bluff," And he'll swear that you're made of the real "eoklier stuff." Twill give bim new hope and the courage to fight For his country and loved ones and honor and right. And he'll say, "For such people I've just got to win And set deair Old Glory afloat o'er Berlin." Then let every woman who's writing today Forget all the sad things she started to say. "God bless you—we love you— we're proud of you, too; We winb we were men, we'd be out there with you." Such a message as this, that breathes hope and cheer, Is worth a round million of those that are drear. With a purpose to cheer, then, do not think it folly In this war-darkened hour to let your letters be jolly. —Anastasla E. Thomas.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://tile.loc.gov/storage-services/service/ndnp/nn/batch_nn_odum_ver01/data/sn83030431/0020029404A/1918051201/1072.pdf
</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>As for German soldier poets there appear to have been hardly any. "Hindenburo . . . has not inspired a single soldier-poet.- " Such soldier verse as the German newspapers have printed has been pretty rhetorical, "noisy rather than strong." Another notable feature of English soldier verse is the absence of what might be called professional patriotism. Yet the English soldier has voiced memorably his love of country the genuine, generally inarticulate, boundless devotion that underlies the English character. It is in Rupert Brooke's famous sonnet :
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030431/1918-05-12/ed-1/seq-74/#words=Harvey+Hodgson+James+Littlejohn+Moncrieff+Poems+Sassoon+Scott+Scott-Moncrieff+Siegfried+war+War
</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Back in Billets , By Charles Scott-Moncrief- f. We're in billets again, and if you please, I shall strap myself up in a Wolsey valise. What's that,, boyf Your boots give you infinite paint You can chuck them away; we're in billets again. We're in billets again now, and, barring alarms, There'll be no occasion for standing to arms, And youll find if you'd many night watches to keep That the hour before daylight's the best hour for sleep. We're feasting on chocolate, cake, currant buns, To a faint German-ban- d obbligato of guns, For I've noticed, wherever the regiment may go, Tliat we always end up pretty close to the foe. But we're safe out of reach of trench mortars and snipers Five inches southwest of the' "Esses" in Ypres; Old Bob, who knows better, pronounces it Yper But don't argue the point now you'll waken the sleeper. Our host brings us beer up, our thirst for to quench, Bo we'll drink him good fortune in English and French : Bob, who finds my Parisian accent a blemish, Goes one better himself in a torrent of Flemish. It's a fortnight on Friday since Christopher died, And John's at Boulogne.with a hole in his side, While poor Harry's got lost, the Lord only knows where; May the Lord keep them all and ourselves in His care. i . . Mustn't think we don't mind when a chap gets laid out, Tliey've taken the. best of us, never a doubt; But with life pretty busy and death rather near We've no time for regret any more' than for fear. . . . Here's a health to our host, Isidore Deschildre, Himself and his wife and their plentiful childer, And the brave aboyeur who bays our return; More power to his paws when he treads by the churn! You may speak of the Rite or the Curzon (Mayfair) And maintain that they keep you in luxury there: If you've lain for six weeks on a waterlogged plain,' Here's the acme of comfort, in billets again.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030431/1918-06-09/ed-1/seq-61/#words=Action+Before+Hodgson+Noel+William
</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030431/1918-10-27/ed-1/seq-37/#words=Charles+Sorley
</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>It is of the poets, Rupert Brooke and Charles Sorley and Alan Mackintosh, W. N. nodgson and Julian GrenfeU, that Mr. Nichols has the most to say. Brooke lies in a beautiful grove of a Greek island, tho others under the tortured soil of Flanders where tho poppies blow. Robert Graves and Siegfried Sassoon are still-alive- with' the marks of many wounds on their bodies and crosses of honor on. their' uniforms. To our own poets of the war, Joyce Kilmer and Alan Seeger and tbe"thers, he pay's the tribute of a comrade-i- arhre anil 'of the pen, but it is of the poets Jf his own country, men he knew in the 'field or "through the few burning words they left, that he wishes to tell us. 'There was Charles Sorley, scarcely known on this side' of the ocean, but in whose death Mascficid said England "suffered her greatest loss in twenty years. v And' Sorley was" only' 20 years'-old'-whe- n' be dropped before the Gcrman'lin'cs 'with a 'bullet through his" heart. A "Viking of a man, moro than six feet tall, with a face on which was marked the sternness oftt 'great purpoe, Sorley Was typical of'fhe'new spirit'of English poetry.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn87096037/1918-09-12/ed-1/seq-6/#war+poets
</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>England With the Allies. While they were in the midst of gory composition, their eyes in a fine frenzy rolling, England entered the war on the side of the allies. This .was distinctly verboteii, and it upset the German plan horribly. England was to stand aside-until Russia and France were annihilated, and then be wiped out in her turn. Anyone who has ever been In Germany knows the fury of a German whose system Is upset. Immediately the mad poets grew madder yet, and the recipient of all their poisoned darts was poor old England. The anger of a German when things are going as he wished Is not a pretty thing, but the anger of the same man when things are going wrong is enough to make God tremble. In this dark hour when all Germany was sputtering with a fury so terrible it seemed words could not be found to express it, Herr Ernst Lissauer came forward and earned the nation'^ gratitude by penning his famous "Hymn of Hate." In our country we are all familiar with this dainty little thing, which ends : 3°. what 'care we for French or Russ? It's a shot for a shot when they shoot at us. We fight our battles with bronze, and steel And when we stop we shall see you kneel! Its you we hate with a lasting hate-^ Nor will we abate one tittle of hate— Hate by water and hate by land, Hate of the head and hate of the hand. Hate of artisan, hate of king. Hate which seventy millions fling; One love they know, one hate they know They know but one, one only foe: England! Little Ernst, groping around in the madhouse, seems to have found words that pretty well/express hijs meaning. In fact, he seems to have put across in fairly effective shape the'idea that the Germans don't c&re much for the English, whichever way you look at It Bat If he hated before, what must have been his fury at the reception his outbreak got in England? Instead of cowering in fear, a laugh went up from the British isles that was heard round the world. The Tommies In the trenches, treated to a German concert,, shouted across :."Sipg us a comic song—sing us the 'Ymn of Hyte.» " And it is recorded In Boyd' Cahle's "Between the Lines* that .Cockney regl. ments, to while a way Idle hours, have been known to sing variations: Hyte of the 'eart and hyte of the *anf 'Oo do we hyte to bet the band: Hingland! Which Is very cruel of them, and en tlrely beyond the comprehension of th< racing foe,
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/2010218519/1919-01-04/ed-1/seq-13/#words=Owen+Seaman
</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>APPOS1LES OF "NO HUMILATION" HBy Owen Seaman. that (Certain the German people nation have proclaimed ought not to their be opinion humili-- jH TJMORS arrive as thick as swarming bees; H Our evening rags announce with raucous clamor The Transmitted latest wire, by the the semiflual fertile Rotterdammer, wheeze jHOf William Giving a Two's local version spontaneous dispersion. jHAVAl They The leave heavy me debt cold. his I deeds care not of wanton how he fury pays owe jHBVMf Whether ho puts his orb to bed, or stays HOn exhibition like an antique curio; ftVMV The reckoning we charge Has to be settled by the Hun at large. jH Here and elsewhere his advocates impute HInnocence to the Boche a gentle creature, HToo prone perhaps to lick the tyrant's boot, HBut otherwise without a vicious feature; HThey'd have our wrath abated; H Poor child, "he must not be humiliated." H Why not? Against his army's bestial crimes HHe never lifted one protesting finger; HThe wrongs of Belgium drew his jocund rimes; H Over the Hymn of Hate he loved to linger, H Pressing the forte pedal, H And wore for luck the Lusitania medal. H He took a holiday for children's slain, BMVJ And butchered women set his flags aflutter; BMVJ Our drowning anguish served for light refrain H To beery patriots homing down the gutter; H On prisoners he spat, BMVj The helpless ones, and thanked his Gott for that. HHad he but fought as decent nations fight, H Clean-hande- then he must have spared his H But now, if Germany goes down in night, H 'Tis he, not we, that puts that shame upon her, H Shame not of mere defeat, HBut such that never our hands again can meet. HWhy should his pride of race be spared a fall? HLet him go humble all his days for sentence. H Why pity him as just a Kaiser's thrall, H This beast at heart tho' fear may fake re-- H pentance? HFor me, when all is said, L-- U I save my pity for our murdered dead. H Punch.
</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-plessy-ferguson/selected-articles
</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86069457/1892-10-13/ed-1/?sp=1&q=JIM&st=text&r=0.255,0.378,0.32,0.391,0
</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE JIM CROW CAR How llio Noparnto Coach Law Work In Texas Negroes UcttlioIIcitot It St Louis Globe Democrat The only grievance the Texas negroes have ia that tho law passed by the retiring Legisla ture requires them to ride in scparato coaches on railroads The traveler about to enter n car anywhero in Texas finds himself confronted at the door uy one of two forms The notice reads For Whites or it reads For Negroes For a whito to ride where it says For Negroes is to vio late a law which subjects him self tho railroad employes per sonally to heavy penalties Thcro is nothing optional about the operation of the law A whito person is shut out as completely from the negroes as tho negro is excluded from tho white car There may be one negro riding in solitary comfort in tho negro conch and 100 white peoplo crowded in dis comfort into tho white coach That makes no difference There can be no mixing The railroads are unable to foresee just what the times It hap pens very frequently that a condition similar to that just mentioned is tho result Thcro arc not scats enough for one race and there are too many for the other race A single illus tration from actual observation may be interesting At Ama rillo ia tho Panhandle two ladies with children a couple of drummers and the usual as sortment of passongcrs boarded the south bound trail at l white coach was full The ne gro compartment was occupied by a Chinaman m soutary stiitc John had turned over tho scat in front and had dis posal of his bags tho heathen always travels with bags in such a way as to prop himself into a very comfortable posi tion Thcro is nothing in tho law which says whites shnll not ride in the negro com partincnt when there are no negroes on board So tho passengers filed in sengers from Amarillo to the negro compartment and proceeded to do as tho China man had done The train had bcimn to move when a solitary negro got on J To took a seat Tho conductor appeared White men women and chil dren were required to get up and movo into the crowded whito coach There a general awakening took place Seats 1 flM l tnl wnn turned juusu uu whole seats wero obliged to double up with those who had none Children cried Every body grumbled A few swore In the compartment for negroes the African and the Chinaman rode with two seats apiece and several others unoccupied for more than 100 miles Not another negro came in all that distance Chinamen Mexicans and Indians aro not classed They rido where they please Probably a very strict and liberal construction of tho law would throw all but tho African on the whito sido of the coach dead lino but tho railroads only observe tho forms to tho decree that will protect them from Cprosccution At first whole coaches wero set apart for tho dilVcrcnt races Now however at tho end of the r 1 c ll l flint tj years tnaioi mum iniin Iacn cvtiuu snnnmted by a partition parts of Texas thcro is almost i 1 On anll no negro irnvui ---roads a small compartment is cut off at ono ond by a thin uunn mid reserved for tho JNW iliiu traveler occasional negro lllalf of tho time it will boun occupied Further south the negro compartments aro larger And ia tho black belt tho coaches arc separated in halves Some roads have the fastenings and grooves so arranged that a partition can bo taken out and moved a few seats forward or backward according as the race proportion of travel changes Negroes do not ride on cars tho year round After cotton pick ing is well under way and sil ver begins to circulate freely there is a great deal of negro travel Later on when tho crop must bo cared for tho negro travel falls to a small fraction To accommodate theso changes the partitions arc so arranged that they can bo moved Tho law makes one exception in favor of negro nurses for whitcchildren This provision is somewhat clastic A lady camo on a train at San Antonio with a robust little Eord Fauntleroy son and a negro lad She planted tho boy in one scat and told tho negro to sit with him while she took the scat in front The negro pro tested Missus ho said I mustnt rido here Thcro is a place where my people have to sit You stav right where you arc tho lady said and proceeded to drill tho negro in his temporary duty as nurso to the ten-year-old youngster in sailor suit and long hair The negro promptly fell asleep and tho boy amused himself by leaning far out tho window The lady having succeeded in doing something tho law said couldnt be done took great satisfaction in watching tho Wjiixiuiv mo nucrocs ofi u Texas do not object to tho scp arato coach act They aro in sured more comfort in travel than they ever had before Theoretically they think tho aw is an outrage because it raises what they call a class distinction The well dressed and well educated negro doesnt like anything which reminds him that ho isnt a white man
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059522/1892-12-21/ed-1/?sp=4&q=TELEGRAPHIC&st=text&r=0.713,0.418,0.229,0.28,0
</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87060004/1892-12-22/ed-1/?sp=2&q=WEDNESDAY&r=0.217,0.512,0.591,0.361,0
</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059523/1896-05-19/ed-1/?sp=1&q=CROW&st=text&r=0.294,0.784,0.32,0.391,0
</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>"JIM CROW" CARS. The Supreme Conrt Siys That They Are Constitutional. WASHINGTON, May 18.—The supreme court of the United States decided today in what is known as the "Jim Crow" car case of Plessy versus Ferguson that the statute of the state of Louisiana, requiring railroad com panies to supply separate coaches for white and colored persons, is constitutional, affirm ing the decision of the court below. Justice Brown delivered the opinion. Justice Harlan dissented.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99021999/1896-05-19/ed-1/?sp=5&q=supreme
</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>WAShINGTON iiay 18.-The supreme court of the United States decided today In vhsat Is known as the "Jim Crow" car case of Plessy agalns F'crguson. that the statute of L3uisiana requiring railroad companle to uppiy epsrate coaches for white anti colored persons itt constitutional affirming the do- Cion of the Court below. Justice hirown delivered the opinion. Jutfce Ilarhan die- soited Ju.tlceWhlto handed down the opnlon of the court In the care of the Singer Sewing machine trademark. The judgment of the court below. the circuit court for the north- era district of Illinois which as against the Singer company was roveraed. The supreme court held that others using the tiamo "Singer" as a trademark should show thin source of manufacture. This case lnvolveil a conflict betneon the Singer Manilfarttirlng company and the Juno Mantifacturing company. The action wee begun gun by the Singer ManufacturIng company to rcatrain the Juno company from making spwInm machines and lnbelin them with time name of "Singer" under the claim that the name which generally attacimeil to time machmiiies made by the Singer company had boconio a trade mark and hence that the 1250 of the nanso by another company was In the nature of an Infringement Jutic White in delivering the opinion of the court held that the right to use a name on articlc.'i Inantlfactureil expired with tle patents on those articies but others itsimig a natmie as in this case lutist show the urco of manufacture. The case wa therefore raver9od awl the district court was directed to enter a decree In accordance with thI3 opinien. Justice harlan delivered the qpinlon of tIme stipremo court In the case 'of Pennington agsinst time tate of Georgia involving tile constitutionality of the state law prohibit- log the running of freight ears in Georgia on Sunday. The opinion held time law to ho valid. Justice Harlan said the legislature hind a right to designate a day of the week when nil labor should be sutmimended and it could not ho claimed that the working day had been mIlgmmated. Time state law was mint lie eaid directed at Interstate commerce but was misemely a rule of civil conduct and it 011st ho respected until superseded by seine national law Itl which it WB in conflict. hence tIme decision of the supreme court was alllrmod. The duet justice and Justice White dlrsented on the groumid that the law conflicts with tIme interstate commerce law. Time supreme court in the case of Martha Ilarmiltz against John 14. Beverly In error to the suplemno court of Kansas revorsmI the decision of the lower court. The opinion was delivered by Justice Shiras. This case was brought on a note for $1,500 and interest but Its decision Involves the constitutionality of tlio mortgage redemption law of Kansas of 1893 and is far reaching in effect. Time case was twice heard in the atate supreme court The opinion In the last hearing was In flovorly's favor holding tIme act in question to be "applicable and. valid in case of contracts tracts made before and after its passage. Time suprenme court reversed this deci.eion holding that no law was valid which proscribed scribed the mode of enforcing a contract in existence when the law was enacted. hIOI.'l' 'VII.L. CASIO IS IN OUIiT. Dncti-i'tit I'onnl itt the Tmi liM Gocit 'i'im ro t Ii 0 ri 'zll of itiv. WASHINGTON May 18.-Time trial of the noted unIt wIll case began today. It. has been pending almost a year. The question at isue is the genmmineness of the alleged wilt of ex-Judgo Advocate John Jeauph helL of Kentucky which was found in the mails of the registrar of wills hero last year. Judge Halt who died in August 1894 was supposed to have died intestate and the val- iiity of the alleged will whose mysterious disappearance caused widespread interest haa boon vigorously contosted. A notable array of counrel was present. Time beneflclaries under the alleged will are Miss Josephine htoit Throclcmorton and Miss Lizzie lImes of Kentucky between whom the estate was equally divided. Luke Derhin a War department cleric was nanmed an executor and for timers appeared ox-Con. gressmas Ii. 3 Butterworth J. J Dariington and flair Leo. Time couneal for time heirs- at-law are ex-Congrezamamm Jero Wilson ox- Anistant Postmaster General Worthington and Mtorneys hleaiy of Washington and Pea. ton of Louisville Ky. The signattmres of Geimoral Sherman and Mrs. W T. Sherman which wore on the will were identified as genuine by Senator Sherman of Ohio and Coionqh Fred Grant of Now York teatified to the genuineness of the aignature of General Grant _ _ _ _ _ htiver nit ilnrhor 11111 iii Cith'retmee. WAShINGTON May 18.-The conferees on time river anti harbor bill expect to have their first report ready tomorrow imight. Of time nate amendments so tar pasea upon thu hmous ha yielded r.bout onts.imalf. Time main qmmostiomms in dispute are time additional contracts autimorized by time senate. Time mtemmato amnenilmemits authorizing contracts tracts to time exteimt of $1,173,000 for Bayou I'iaquemmmine. Loulelamma and the imommso provision vision o $315,000 for the Caicaslen river Loitislatma together witim time Delaware river projects time boat railway on time Columbia river and time Lake Union mimi Washimmgton aisal at Seattle Wash are Limo nialu points ttiil in dispute. It is quite probable that no I igreenment will be reported on them at rescnt.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84025841/1896-05-23/ed-1/?sp=2&q=decision+DECISION+supreme+SUPREME&st=text&r=-0.056,-387.738,1.111,776.667,0
</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>ANOTHER DECISION The Supreme Court of the United States on Monday, May 18, 1896 ren? dered a decision in the case of Plessy against Ferguson sustaining the con? stitutionality of the law of Louisiana requiring the railroad' of the State tc provide separate cars for white and colored passengers. Justice Harlan dissented. This is another practical demonstration ol the effect of public sentiment upon ev? en the greatest judicial body in the world. We can be discriminated against, we can be robbed of our political rights, weean be persecuted and murdered and yet we cannot secure a legal re? dress in the courts of the United States. Truly Las evil days come up? on us. But a reckoning day will come and all classes of citizens, sooner or la? ter realize that a government which will not protect cannot demand for it? self protection. The national government is being brought within very narrow limits, that of the territories and the District of Columbia and if the present con 1*1 aaaaSBI tion ot the law is many mare j nictated it will be a great to be Governor than it will to bel idetit of the Tinted States. vbby statement made bj kn vTin upon the occasion of her w>e< consistent with her Ibam> :e and no declaration made by her indicative of her guilt.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86069395/1896-05-26/ed-1/?sp=5&q=separate+coaches+SEPARATE+COACHES&st=text&r=0.081,0.047,0.486,0.594,0
</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>SEPARATE Cd ACHES. JJ Held to be Constitutional! by V. 8. Stpreme Court, Washington, May 118. The Su preme Court of the Uriited States decided to-day, in what is known as the "Jim Crow'' car case of Plessy vs. Ferguson, that the statute of the State of Louisiana requiring railroad companies to supply separate coaches for white and colored persons, is constitutional, affirming the decision of the court below. Justice Brown delivered the opinion. Justice Harlan dissented. A similar case from Kentucky is now in the United States Court of Appeals, having been taken up from the Federal Circuit Court of the Kentucky district, in which Judge Barr held that the law WilH linnnnstifnrinn. al.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87075213/1900-06-28/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Jim+Crow+JIM+CROW&st=text&r=0.494,0.991,0.21,0.256,0
</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>l"or Jim Crow Street Cars. New Orleans, June 28. The lower branch of the state legislature passed an act to compel separate equal ac commodations for blacks and whites nn Ntreet cur lines, by a vote ot 81 to 5. The senate will also probably pass It-
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85025007/1900-07-03/ed-1/?sp=3&q=SEPARATE+separate+BILL&st=text&r=-0.056,-387.627,1.111,776.667,0
</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE 8EPARATE CAR BILL. Tbe Epbee separate cai bill, which went into effect at midnight Saturday? had its first trial on Sunday, when there was twice as much travcd by negroes as on any other day, and the new law went into operation without dilSculty as far as heard from on tbe roads enter? ing Richmond. Tbe railroads haul ample notice and prepared cars in ad? vance. Meet of tbe cars are separated by a partition across a few seats in one end of each car. These compartments, it is understood, will be un?d for colored people when travel ia light, aud when it is heavy an extra car will be used. When the extra car is used then these compartments will be utilized as "smok? ers," and there will be no regular smok? ing-car .-."The accommodation for whites and blacks are identical. The only objection raised by tbe col? ored people 90 far is tbeir inability to buy second-class tickets, they having been aboliebed under tbe new order of things. Tbe law requiring separate cars is styled. "The act providing for separate railway coaches lor whit? and colored people," but what is known as tbe "Jim Crow Law." Tbe act was passed and approved on January 30, 1900, and tbe railroads were given five months to make preparations lor the change. The law consists of nine sections, which provide, in substance, as follows: Section 1 provides for separate coaches on all steam railroads in Vir glnia. Suction 2 forbids discrimination in the quality, acconiinodationn and con? veniences of the cars for the white and colored. Section 3 makes tbe violation of sec? tions 1 and 2 a misdemeanor and fixes the punishment at a line of not less than $300 nor more than $1,000. Section 4 gives county and city courts, in whose counties and cities railroads are operated, jurisdiction over the offenses in section Section 5 gives the conductor of a train power to put oil tbosa who re? fuses to occupy the cars provided for them. Section 6 makes failure of conductors to comply with section 5 a misdemean? or and fixes a fine of not less than $25 nor more than $50 for euch Henee. Section 7 gives a conductor the priv? ilege of putting persons out of the coach or compartment of coach provid? ed for tbem if the one provided is full and no other is available. Section 8 state* tbe exception to tbe law as follows: Employees of railroads, persons employed as nurses, officers in charge of prisoners, passengers in any caboose car attached to a freight train, Pullman cars and through or express trains which do no local business. Section 9 states time when law goes into effect?July 1, IMO.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84025841/1904-04-30/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Jim+Crow+JIM+CROW&st=text&r=0.48,0.552,0.286,0.349,0
</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>RICHMOND'S JIM CROW CARS. Of all the towns beneath the stars, Oli Richmond beats for Jim Crow cars. They thread her streets and all around Her suburbs Jim Crow cars abound. And some are fast and some are slow, But in the rear all serve Jim Crow. The smokers on the rear platform Can joke and smoke when cold or warm; In wide spread door conductor stands, Ihat joke and smoke of vilest brands Throughout the rear may freely flow And fill the space kept for .Tim Crow. In summer time they'll smoke Jim Crow; In winter time when bleak winds blow. Jack Frost will stalk through open door. And killing draughts will always pour. Upon those who shall hold the row Of feats in rear kept for Jim Crow. But the summer cars, when they shall go To the lakes where pleasant breezes blow; Refreshing air of day or night Will strike alike the black and white! And Jim Crow then will have his rights, And lair ?s well as any whites! But will he though! But will he though Who hold the two rear seats I By Joe! Those seats belong to him who smokes And loves to crack his ribald jokes. And swift wind from the rear will blow These sweet things to our dear Jim Grow. It is the principle involved, Ah all will see when all is solved, Which now enigmatic may seem To those who do not wake, but dieani: 'Tis rights of man! make here no balk? Man's rights we claim! For these we wain. ?O. M. Steward. On the liiirlit Track. [BALTIMORE, MDS., AKRO-AMERICAN LKDOER.]
</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-building-titanic/selected-articles
</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042462/1908-04-23/ed-1/?sp=1&q=White+Star+line&r=0.615,0.243,0.402,0.246,0
</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1908-10-02/ed-1/?sp=9&q=White+Star+line&r=-0.679,0.36,2.357,1.44,0
</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1909-01-03/ed-1/?sp=59&q=White+Star+Titanic&r=0.523%2C0.839%2C0.612%2C0.374%2C0&st=text
</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Ireland. The steamers whose keel blocks haT» I been laid side by side in this the biggest gantry j In the world are the Titanic and th« Olympic, of the White Star Line, and within a year or two I these leviathans will b« running between New Tori* and Southampton. Soon after the two fast Cunarders. too Lusl- I taria and the Mauretania, had demonstrated that I one could travel in luxury and at a very high i speed through tha agency of turbine engines. th« White Star X-in» announced that it would build two steamers to beat the Oinarders la length and breadth, and perhaps In other ways also. It was reported at the tim» that th« new Whlta Star liners would be a thousand feet in length, but sub sequently it was officially announced that they i would bo 900 feet lons, with a beam of ninety feet. j When It was decided to build them it was found that there was no gantry In thm world big enough to accommodate such monsters, and It was then that H&rland Wolff began to rip up three of Its largest gantries and build the hug* steel and con crete cradle that Is now ready to bold th* Olympic and the Titanic. Before th* steel structure which supports th* i powerful electric travailing cranes was erected a big concrete base, twenty fret thick, was built upon sp!le3 driven fifty fe«t into tha ground. The con crete foundation, in addition to being more firm than the regular earthen base, has the advantage of cleanliness, an 1 tools and materials which mar fall from the cranes la the course of construction may be found more readily. Parts of deck fittings end tools have fallen into the ground la gantries with earth bases and have not been recovered until the vessel has gilded from Its cradle into the water. The construction of the Olympic has been started. The keel of the Titanic will be laid soon, and visitors to the shipyards at Belfast will have an opportunity of seeing the simultaneous csnstrcs tion. side by side, of the largest two steamers tn the world. The gantries are so built that any piece of material, however heavy or awkward, may be placed and held In whatever position the con atructora desire. The gantries themselves are more than a thousand feet in length. 3C3 feet high and something more than two hundred feet la -Ki&X T
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1909-05-30/ed-1/?sp=59&q=White+Star+Titanic
</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>TWO XEW GIAXTS OF SEA. The Titanic and the Olympic W3l lie Largest Steamships in World. Although what will be the largest two steamships In the world, the Titanic and the Olympic, of the White Star Line, are mere skeletons just now in their Lie million-dollar double gantry at Belfast, Ireland the marine architects know exactly bow they are going to look when they start on their maiden passage to this port. From the plans and specifications the designers have made a wush drawing showing bow 'he monsters will look when In the water and ready to sail. Although at nrst glance the illustration suggests the Isauretania and Lusitania. with their four gigantic funnels, there Is something in the appearance of the new levia thans that Is typical of a White Star steamship. The great height of the new liners and the broad sweep of the bridge elves some idea of their 80.J80 tons displacement. The builders have almost elimi nated the old cusr im of carying masts, «nd In this respect the targesi ships in the world resemble the Old Dominion steamers, tha smallest passenger carrying vessels in the American coastwise service. All the old Dominior Mners have only one mast. g the 1 ;i' i Titanic. Thrse tw< vessels are being built simultaneously sid* by side In a steel gantry that was begun a year before the keels were laid, and which cost over a million dollars. The new liners will each n«» S» feet long, with 92-foot beam. The unusual beam la equivalent to the length of some of the fast utenrn yachts of this port. The Olympic and Titanic will iw» read] for the New York. South ampton an.i Cherbourg *»*r\ im of the White Star IJne in 1911. The builders are Harland a Wolff.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn93063916/1910-01-08/ed-1/?sp=1&q=White+Star+Titanic&st=text&r=0.207,0.611,0.509,0.621,0
</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE TITANIC NOW NO BEING BUILT Here la an architectural picture of the steamship Titanic which Is being beingbuilt beingbunt beingbuilt built for the White Star line at Belfast also a view of the giant steel cradle cradleiu iu which the ship Is being constructed The keel of the steamship Is seen in inthe inthe inthe the lower photograph The White Star company Is to have two of these theselaviathans theselebtthans theseleviathans leviathans and they will be In commission early in 1911 Their launching launchingwill will UI signalize a most important era in marine achievement for they will be bobyc beby beby byc byctil by all odds the largest vessels in the world The Titanic and Olympic will willench wUlh willeach each h be SCO feet f t in length 92 feet beam 45000 tons register and GOOOO tons tonsdisplacement tonsdl tonsdlstixccnwnt displacement dl Ilem nt These enormous dimensions are best expressed In comparl comparlS 30115 S The Washington Va hlngton monument is r x55 55 5 feet high and the Metropolitan tower towerlit lit New Xt York rliy r f ity rises TOO feet Tbe combined tonnage tonnn e of tbe Olympic Olympicand OIrJ11pllukl and Tlrxink k far fn r exceeds the tonnage ton n e of all It II the vrbs vessels tssl els ls engaged pn n ngld tM1 on both bothskies bothkles bothskies skies In the hlsi hI Irlt rl conflict of the Spanish armada HfuJ dn Hud nd It Is even more In Interesting Inttresrln inttirestinx teresting to know ihir t t the Santa Maria was only em I rIt ii 0 feet fi Plat i t Ions IOll a and d 233 tons tonsvet tonhtnhn tonelnirien htnhn t vet tat nn thl visw yf f 4r1 1 Columbus Journeyed TO th thp new UP world
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045433/1910-01-23/ed-1/?sp=14/&q=White+Star+Titanic
</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1910-07-11/ed-1/?sp=3&q=White+Star+Titanic&st=text&r=-0.251,-0.155,1.031,1.031,0
</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>IFli; or NEW LINERS SOON 10 BE LAUNCHED Hr Carlisle Says Olympic and Titanic Will Be Handsomest Vessels Afloat. LiOMSTER.S OF 45.000 TONS tvrert Says There Is No Reason '•'■■7 They Should Not. Be x Ha-^ ec Praise fin Americans. Vs rt r VT ah!*' "Alexander M Car '~*r r*""e^2^ 'Tir'l— Of the big shipbuild-. i r-r Z Harlassd Wolff, at Belfast. r%r^*£T.d probably the most prominent |g!Swj) constructor in Great Britain, ar- T^an yesterday en the .Whit* Star »T^> r, of the vessels "which grew *F, o^servatioti in the Belfast yards. i-T^ •"s-i-t bssb Bf about sixty, and has .**^i-v tie Crsa he represents for forty; **^~~ezzs According c his friends he is f: _.."- talks little, but. thinks much. s .rCl crpt-ired —1? yesterday when he j^**^v V about the new-, theusand-fect c t2.r eiants that are seen to leave Kr^,;^ Vt Belfast -vT~s -=thir.g at all to say." said Mr fejjsie iSraptly. tm not S" c to talk S-TsSlps What "have" I com© over- for" W--V2 SStle trip and the salt baths. rcirg right back en the Oceanic on VfeSaai jri-ec t-"- e £e2 waase at Belfast was J.. r -«t £5 coed se the salt water of the r, J^ r of Vfeew York, Mr Carlisle replied s'-spese S&! But you see I came over to 2*iitt2s» at sea: to get the sea air %i tie salt t-stis or. board the Celtic" Cr tie tie bay Carlisle clung v^c^v remark that he -would not T ,v ajjsst ships, but he asksd many ques .j.,., ibbct tie harbor and the cutters that aX tie Celtic By degress v,«, warmed up 7. -_;* cibject o* stear^ship construction, to •rt^zz. he hsi obßd his life, and declared £2* Clynplc and Titanic would but* p^serSsenr ark -"--er- they cams here in 3£-
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1911-05-31/ed-1/?sp=5&q=titanic&st=text&r=0.403,0.369,0.579,0.707,0
</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>MONSTEB LINER LAUNCHED. Steamer Titanic Slides Into Water at Belfast. BELFAST, May .11.?Enthusiastic crowds lined the banks of the River l Star line's great steamer Titanic was launched with appropriate ceremonies this morning. The Titanic will enter the White Star's New York-Soutl^ampton service late in the year, but her sister vessel Olympic steams from Southampton two weeks hence for New York, and these two sea monsters, each 45,000 tons register, 882Vt feet long and 92 H fo*t broad, boast the distinction of being the largest and finest, vessels in the world These massive ships are also notable for the enchanting beauty and the un usual spaciousness of their passenger ac commodations, and in first, second and third class the greatest comfort is prom ised. On both steamers swimming pools, tennis and hand ball courts, and Turkish and electric bath establishments ars among the Innovations introduced for the pleasure of the passengers.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86086633/1912-04-03/ed-1/?sp=1&q=titanic
</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>TITANIC'S MAIDEN TRIP. Sister Ship to the Olympic of White Star Line Snls Next Week. Lorn! on, April The gigantic new st Mam-ship Titanic of thr White Star line arrive.) todoy at Setithamptt n from the MinN of her bulkiers at H-l- fast. She is to be marie re.iriy for herj maitlen trip across the Atlantl the atnri al ertotch la scheduled for sVed. Oaaday af next week. The Titanic is a sister ship to the Olympic. 8he Is 0 leet hmg and has a d b placement of r.o 000 tons. The travellmr Ust n the bb ship will have coo names "Hi its brt lass roll, in addition to 500 BOO ot l i lass and third cabin oa sengt ts. To this will be adder, the n v oi sua makina a t ui tlo.tiiiK pojsilatlon of mir1y t.ooe.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86058226/1912-04-10/ed-1/?sp=1&q=titanic+titantic
</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>TITANTIC SAILS ON HER FIRST VOYAGE White Star Liner the Largest Vessel that Ever Sailed the Seas. (National News Association) LONDON, April 10. Carrying 1400 passengers the liner Titanic of the White Star line, than which there is no larger vessel afloat, sailed from Southhampton today on her maiden voyage bound for New York. The Tt tanic which is of 45,000 tons displace ment Is sister ship to the Olympic. All the special suites of rooms in stituted as an innovation in the Titan ic were occupied when the passage be gun. These suites consist of bed rooms, sitting room, bath room, and servant's room and have their own private deck promenade isolated from the rest of the ship and not overlooked by any other passengers. The Titanic also possesses another new feature in its Louis XVI. restaur ant. Her sister ship the Olympic, also has this feature but on a smaller scale. It proved so popular, however,, that the White Star company decided to have Jhe one on the Titanic greatly enlarged. Adjacent to it is a special reception room for the use of passen gers taking meals in the restaurant. The Titanic while its engineering principal is the same as that of the Olympic, is expected by experts on navigation to make faster time than the Olympic because of a slight dif ference in the curvature of the propel ler blades.
</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-early-electric-cars/selected-articles
</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88064454/1891-10-31/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Carriage+carriage+electric+Electric&st=text&r=0.415,0.784,0.32,0.391,0
</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Building an Electric C'arriage. A novelty among vehlieles in this country, an electric carriage, is now beinig coni)strucllted at the faet'rv of IM. W. Qutinlan, in Brookline. Mass., front plans drawn front a photograph of a similar carriage in nresent use in London. The battery contains thirty. two cells,aoid is jplaced in the rear end of the body of 4ileo carriage. The motor, which is of foreign manutfao ture, rests between the hitd springs, where it is attached to the body by two hinge clasps in such a manner as to allow it to swing when the motion of the carriage is irregular, although this swing is regulated by a connect ing rod. The driving shfts of the miotor extetd on eithcir side ibeyond lthe sprinigs, and are fitted wilh cog wheel attachittents which coninect by atln endless chlati with larger cogwheels on the inner side of the rear wheels. Thie steering apparatus is on the left side of the carriage platform. In case of accildent to the amotor, shafts can be litted to the c:u'riage, and horses at. tached. When comnileted, tie whole carriage will weighl about 2500 pouttds. All tlhe electrical work is tlone by the loltiier-Cabot Cotl,:ny*. -[New York ''Tribune.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024546/1891-12-09/ed-1/?sp=12&q=carriage+electrical&st=text&r=-0.01,0.488,0.2,0.2,0
</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>SCRAPS OF SCIENCE. Odd Pieces of Mechanism Evolved by Meditative Brains. ELECTRICITY TLAYS ITS PACT. Carriages and Fans Are Iropelled Yitll out Animal Energy. PAVEMENTS MADE FROM OAK AND ICON An electrical carriage has been shipped to Chicago from Des Moines, Iowa. It may arrive to-day, and as soon as its storage bat teries can be charged it will be sent spin ning alont; the boulevards. It was built for ordinary usage and it is said to have carried 12 people at a speed ot 14 miles an hour and can run continuously for 13 hours be fore the energy is exhausted. The motor ued is rated at four-horse power, and has an armature of the Siemens type with special-wound coils. The prominent feature of the carriage is the storage cells, 24 in number placed in three sets of eight each. The weight is said to be but 32 pounds per cell audio yield three-horse power hours of energy per cell. The carriage ha a special gearing and a ball and socket motion to the axle, while a peculiar hub device allows for any obstacles encountered. The motor is carried by a framework underneath the body of the car riage and is geared to the rear axle. The steering device is attached to the front uf the axle and is controlled bv a handwheel in the front of the carriage. It is said to be so delicate in action that the course of the chicle can be altered bv a slight touch. The switch for throwing the motor in and out ot circuit is moved by the foot of the one in charge. This carriage is said to have ascended grades or 17 per cent without severe strains. A Frenchman has invented an electric gas-leak detector, which is something like an aneroid barometer. It consists of a acuum chamber working a contact piece. The diaphragm is dilated by the pressure of the gas, and by means ot a lever arm placed on the diaphragm an electric contact is made, ringing a bell. The instrument is said to be ery delicate, and its utility will be appreciated in large factories where much gas is used.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059522/1892-08-11/ed-1/?sp=5&q=electricity+Electricity+Morrison+wagon+Wagons+William&st=text&r=0.32,-0.017,0.27,0.33,0
</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>GOOD BYE, HORSES I Wagons May Now Be Run by Electricity. Chicago, Aug, 10.— A novelty in the way of a wagon propelled by electricity was seen on the streets of Chicago yes terday. Some time ago President J. B. McDonald, of the American Battery company, purchased several patents from William Morrison, of Dcs Moines. Among other things was a park wagon equipped with a small three-horse-power motor and twenty-four-cell storage bat tery. Yesterday Mr. McDonald fitted the wagon with new batteries and gave it a trial. With five persons in the wagon it left the barn on Monroe street and traveled to the company's office. The run was made in twenty two minutes, which was considered a satisfactory, considering that the wagon was delayed at a bridge and that fre quent stops were, made on account of the crowds in the streets down town. It is calculated that the wagon can make ten miles an hour easily with the present motor and can climb any bill in the city.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1895-12-03/ed-1/?sp=10&q=carriage+carriages+Company+company+electric+Electric+electricity+Morris+Salom+Wagon+wagon+wagons&r=0.146%2C0.314%2C0.686%2C0.419%2C0&st=text
</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The owners of the electric wagons did not start out with the idea of winning the race. They were unable to arrange for sup ply stations at different places along the route and consequently could not get enough power to run over the route to Evanston and back. Dut they Intended to show that their electric wagons could travel under all con ditions us well as the gasoline motor ma chines, anel they considered their test proved the practicability of electricity for horseless carriages.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1896-02-02/ed-1/?sp=25&q=Carriage+carriage+carriages+electric+Electric+electrical+electricity+Horseless+horseless+Morris+Salom+wagon&st=text&r=0.28,0.49,0.213,0.26,0
</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The "PJlectrqbat 1 is the original name given by Morris Salom of Philadelphia j to the first electric wagon constructed in i that city. It was ihe joint work of a me- chanical engineer and an electrician. The i wagon was run hundreds of miles over the streets of Philadelphia without seri- j i ous mishap. Its tot.il weight, including I the battery, is 4250 pounds, and the max;- j mum mileage on one charge of electricity la from h'fty to one hundred, according to j speed and grades, the maximum speed at- j tamable being- fifteen miles an hour. Charles A. Duryea of Peoria, 111., ha 3 successfully applied the gasoline motor to horselessvehici.es. The Duryea motor re sembles an ordinary, heavily buih buggy, weighs 700 pounds,* and has ball-bearings An Electrobat.
</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
